CORMAC MCGLOIN

PRODUCT DESIGNER

Skills

User-centred design

User research

User interface design

Wireframes

Interaction design

Information architecture

User journeys

Task flows

Coded prototypes

Tools

Figma

Sketch

Photoshop

Illustrator

InDesign

After Effects

Framer

Principle Zeplin

Programming

HTML 5

CSS 3

SASS/SCSS

Javascript

React

JQuery

Greensock

Git

Education

Bachelor of Arts, Photography

University of East London

2008 - 2011

National Diploma, Graphic Design

Wigan and Leigh College

2004 - 2006

About me

I'm a design consultant who helps businesses understand their customers and improve their products. Combining an eye for design with a methodical approach to research and frontend development skills means that I have taken projects from the planning stages right through to implementation and beyond. I have experience working within the agile methodology and scrum framework.

Experience

Senior product design consultant (contract)

Moneyfarm | August 2020 - January 2021

Helped to deliver optimised website and app experiences by improving the consistency and efficiency of the design system. The work I did allowed the design team to communicate more effectively with other teams.

Senior design consultant (contract)

Zoopla (via 101 Ways) | June 2019 - March 2020

Instrumental in the planning, designing and implementation of a centralised design system at Zoopla. This led to increased consistency for the end users, greater efficiency for the designers and engineers and an improved onboarding experience for new team members.

Senior UI designer (contract)

Arroe | November 2018 - Present

Designing the website and app for their smart battery. Packaging design for the product and collateral for the business.

Senior UI designer (contract)

River Island | July 2018 - March 2019

Improving the user experience throughout the River Island site. Research methodologies included, competitor analysis, white paper research, data analysis, in-person interviews, usability testing and multivariate testing.

Senior UI designer (contract)

Havas Life Medicom | June 2018

Producing user interface designs for a pharmaceutical website.

Email designer & developer (contract)

Harrods | April - May 2018

Designing and developing various email campaigns for Harrods and their brand partners.

Senior UI designer (contract)

Beauty Pie | January - March 2018

Reviewing UI patterns to help create a unified design language and make the user journey more intuitive. Hosting daily calls with developers to aid with code implementation.

Senior UI designer (contract)

Spafax | November - December 2017

Producing user interface designs and style guides for the websites of various airlines.

Lead designer & lead front-end developer (contract)

Catapult Sports | July - October 2017

Lead designer and front-end developer for the new PlayerTek website.

Senior UI & iOS designer (contract)

Arroe | May - June 2017

Designing a concept app and single-page website for a new tech product.

Senior UI designer (contract)

Topshop | February - June 2017

Helped to unify the desktop and mobile user experiences by creating consistent UI patterns across all device sizes and producing a style guide that would be the single source of truth.

Senior UX/UI designer (contract)

Hudson Shoes | July 2016 - February 2017

Redesigned key pages of the website including the homepage, PLP, PDP and checkout journey. Designed and coded key landing pages and email campaigns.

Digital & print designer (contract)

Lufthansa | September - December 2016

Producing digital and print designs for Lufthansa and its subsidiaries.

Senior UI designer (contract)

Practicology | May - July 2016

Designing key pages for the Hobbycraft and Dreams websites.